[♪♪♪]
[Ras coughing]
Clear your mind,
then begin.
Do I hear celebration pies?
[together] Oh, pies!
-[all talking excitedly]
-Oh, those smell so good.
[gobbling]
What are you waiting for?
Go!
Now...
transfer Spinjitzu momentum
to one of the stones.
[growling]
Another failure!
I see mental conflict in you.
It's nothing.
I'll try again.
You're thinking
about the Ninja.
Forget those cowards and fools.
They're not cowards.
They might have made
some mistakes,
but they're heroes.
"Hero"?
That word is meaningless.
To some, I'm a hero.
[coughing]
It's easy to be a hero
to those who agree with you,
and a villain
to those who don't.
But the Ninja
have saved the world.
[growling]
They didn't save mine!
[coughing]
No one did!
You've never told me
what happened--
And they didn't save
your parents.
I blame Master Wu for that.
As you should.
[coughing]
[gasping in pain]
You're weak.
I am injured, not weak.
Never mistake the two.
But you're getting worse.
Yes.
[wincing]
I am dying...
[gasping]
and with me,
your chances
of finding your parents.
Our only hope
is deep inside
the Spectral Lands.
We must continue on.
What even are
the Spectral Lands?
They are dark lands
for those that are
no longer living.
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja
for what's right ♪
[♪♪♪]
So, no rumors
on your travels
of a certain Ninja
that shoots lightning
and makes bad jokes?
No, but in the Endless Sea,
I did get shocked
by an electric eel.
Does that help you?
[Nya] I can't believe
it's come to this...
asking randos in the street
where the love of my life
could be.
What else can we try?
We've been all over the place
and found nothing.
Jay's better at disappearing
than Mr. Pale.
Maybe we don't need
to find Jay.
Maybe we just bring Jay to us.
Sure, brilliant!
Oh, except how?
You wanna attract lightning,
you put up a lightning rod,
and that's our lightning rod.
[Nya] "Grand opening
of Lobbo's Totally Rad Arcade,
Lobbo-Lobbo"?
That guy will throw his money
into any terrible business idea.
Lobbo's Arcade has
a Galamorph X-Post cabinet.
Eh? Eh?
[sighing]
There was a GX-P
in Ed and Edna's junkyard
where Jay grew up.
He was speed-running it
since he was a kid,
and is still
the high-score record holder.
It's his favorite game!
So?
So get this--
I've been practicing GX-P
on an emulator.
I think I've got the skills
to finally beat his high score,
and if that happens,
he'll come from anywhere
in the Merged Lands
to take back his top spot.
Jay doesn't have
his memory, Kai.
He won't remember
Gala-post-morph...
Galamorph X-post.
He won't even remember
it exists.
No matter
what's happened to Jay,
no matter
if his goodness is shattered,
or his memory gone,
wherever he is,
whatever he's doing,
if his high score is broken,
he'll feel it, and he'll come.
Why would Jay be so crazy
about a video game?
They're super boring.
All that grammar and spelling.
I played every game
in my Caregiver Bot's
memory banks,
and they were all the worst.
"Carrying the one."
"Using proper manners."
Blech!
Oh, Wyldfyre.
I predict this is going to be
a very big day for you.
[grunting with effort]
[thudding and wincing]
[Arin grunting, Ras grumbling]
I'm guessing
that's the Spectral Lands?
Yes.
Hurry.
[thudding and groaning]
I'm sorry,
I don't think
I can get you in there safely.
Tell me what I need
to get for you.
No. I-I must--
[coughing and wheezing]
You can't make it,
and we're losing time.
Tell me what you need.
[Ras wheezing]
After the Merge,
there were legends.
I... I need...
healing elixir
from the Well of the Lost.
Well of the Lost. Got it.
Any clue where it is in there?
Village center...
hilltop.
Okay, you stay here.
Save your energy. I'm going in--
Arin!
Returning Blade.
Prismatic steel.
You...
will need it.
On it!
Don't die on me, Ras.
[shivering]
This place is freezing.
Okay, not seeing
any dead people... yet.
Wow.
This is just...
Welcome, customers,
to Lobbo's Totally Rad Arcade,
Lobbo-Lobbo!
Home to some games
Lobbo invented,
for example,
Whack-a-Lobbo!
For some reason, that's
Lobbo's mom's favorite game.
And here is the Lobbo-Roll-O!
All completely new
and original gaming concepts,
trademark Lobbo Industries.
Lobbo-Lobbo.
Wow, Lobbo.
This is so... fun.
Is that the right word?
Look, we're here for--
[Lobbo] A delicious meal?
Lobbo has you covered!
Lobbo's world-famous
endless Casserole Pit!
Lobbo-Lobbo!
[belching]
Actually, we're here for
the Galamorph X-post machine.
Ah, a retro gamer!
Good choice!
Even if it could use
a Lobbo-themed update.
Lobbo-Lobbo.
[gasping in delight]
Hello, old friend.
Your Kai guy is back.
Really?
Ignore her.
She's just jealous.
You honestly think
this dumb plan
has even the slightest chance
of working?
You have a better idea
we should try instead?
I wonder if they got that
"Organize your bedroom" game.
I was pretty good at that one.
[game music playing]
[Wyldfyre] What?
This has nothing to do
with bedroom organization.
There's video games
where you can blast stuff?
Wait...
can video games be exciting?!
[cackling in delight]
Whoa! [gasping]
[struggling]
[branches creaking]
[shutters slamming]
[gasping] H'yah!
[debris clattering]
Returning Blade?
Nice.
Why was Ras
keeping this thing a secret?
"Village Center, Hilltop."
It's gotta be this way--
Whoa!
Watch out, buddy!
You're messing
with the wrong guy today!
[nearby snarling]
Get down!
[blows thudding]
What is going on?
You have prismatic steel!
Why aren't you
looking through it?
Whoa...
[beast snarling]
[Arin gasps]
[snarling]
There are nodes on its back.
Strike them!
H'ah!
Yeah!
Eat that,
weird invisible ugly beast!
Problem solved.
Not solved.
Why not?
[distant snarling]
They hunt in packs.
[♪♪♪]
[munching]
[furious blasting]
[grunting in frustration]
[groaning]
[game sounds]
[rapid beeping and blasting]
[Lobbo]
Tuna Gelatin, with mints!
-[yelping]
-[casserole belching]
[beeping and blasting]
[laughing excitedly]
[groaning in frustration]
[distant screeching of beasts]
I gotta get you out of here.
Soul-Suckers like draining
the spirit energy of the living
even more than the dead.
Dead... like you?
Of course.
This place
is only for the Departed.
Living people
should never come here,
so let's go
before those things come back.
I can't leave.
I need something.
You're going to be killed!
What could you possibly need
from here?
Elixir from something
called the "Well of the Lost."
[beast snarling]
I'm a Ninja,
and my...
my teacher is dying.
I was once a Ninja,
and I know masters
are very important.
[beast snarling closer]
I know where the well is.
Keep close
if you want to stay alive.
[snarling]
Yeah, I'd like to stay alive.
[beasts screeching]
Oh, man, oh, man...
I've never made it
to this level before.
I-- Uh-- Uh--
[victorious beeping]
[cheering]
I did it! I did it!
Well, I finally beat you, Jay!
[laughing]
Time for you
to defend your high score!
Come on,
even if this does work,
it's not like he'd be
instantly teleported to--
[door banging open]
[gasping]
[dove cooing]
Oh, hey, guys!
Uh, were you all waiting for me?
Who are you again?
[cooing like a dove]
I knew this wouldn't work.
Give it time, sis.
He'll be here.
Maybe it'll help
if I play more games.
Yeah, I'll do that.
For Jay.
[screeching]
I thought the Departed Realm
was where everyone went
when they died.
Why are you and those monsters
the only things here?
Oh, the Departed Realm
was way messed up
even before the Merge
turned it into
the Spectral Lands.
We had the Cursed Realm
end up inside here,
so when the Merge happened,
both realms
got all mixed together.
It's a mess. Let's go.
But shouldn't there be
more Departed Souls here
than just you?
After the Merge,
the Departed were finally
able to move on.
"Move on"?
To where?
I don't know.
Another phase of existence?
To be reborn?
Beats me,
but I like to think
they go to eternal rest,
and when people die,
they still come here,
but they only pass through,
and as they do,
they're vulnerable
to Soul-Suckers,
so I protect them.
Why haven't you moved on?
Sometimes I feel the pull
to do just that,
but I told you, I was a Ninja,
and I've decided it's my duty
to protect everyone
who passes through here.
even if they happen
to still be alive.
We're here.
[sighing]
We've waited long enough.
Ah, maybe we should hit
all the other arcades
in the city.
For Jay.
Let's just go.
[beeping and whooshing]
Look!
Someone
is playing it remotely,
which on an old-school cabinet
like this
shouldn't be possible.
That style...
two blasts
after each rocket boost!
Only one person
plays GX-P like that.
So... you're not gonna say who?
What is this stuff?
[Departed Soul] Don't ask me.
Drinking it
is what helps souls move on,
but for the living,
it can sometimes
provide healing.
Your master will be pleased.
I don't think
my teacher does "pleased."
Masters
can be tough sometimes.
I had a... complicated
relationship with mine,
and I betrayed him,
my biggest regret.
That's why I stay here
to help people.
My master was wise.
He taught me to defend those
who cannot defend themselves,
so I honor his teachings
to make up for my mistakes.
That's really... noble.
[distant beasts screeching]
Okay, now, let's get you
out of here.
[game beeping and shuddering]
Aw, come on.
I spent all day
rocking that high score!
Now it's about to--
No! [sobbing]
[Nya] "Jay"!
It's really him.
We get you across the border,
and the Soul-Suckers
can't follow you.
I don't know how to thank you.
Just stay alive.
Aah!
H'ah!
[distant snarling]
[shouting] Ah!
Ah... the elixir.
[groaning]
Run!
Get out of the Spectral Lands!
I'm not leaving you!
Ras! No!
[gasping and groaning]
[Ras groaning]
Come on, Ras, don't die on me.
The elixir
from the Well of the Lost
can take time to work,
but it's always effective.
Your master?
He's... my teacher.
Looks like he taught you well.
Thank you for everything.
I wish I could repay you.
You know, you could do
one thing for me.
If you ever run into my master,
let him know...
he was right.
Of course.
Who was your master?
His name is Wu.
Master Wu?
But...
but he's dead.
No, he must be alive.
If he had departed, I'd know.
He would have
come through here.
[distant beasts screeching]
Now it's really time
for you to go.
[unsheathing weapon]
You're wrong, Ras.
The word "hero"
isn't meaningless.
[beasts screeching]
Sometimes it's
the only word that fits.
More travelers?
How can we be
of service to you?
[Rox] Find it!
[villagers screaming]
There's no reason
to do this to our home!
We will help you
with anything you need.
[explosion]
That's it.
[Thunderfang] On time.
Right when I expected.
How could you know
we were coming?
You still haven't
figured it out,
Rox of the Wyldness?
Everything you've ever done
has been according to my plan.
You lie.
You've been chained down here
for millennia,
helpless,
but we have
a deal to make with you.
[cackling menacingly]
The ego...
The entitlement!
You remind me of my young self.
Let me guess,
this deal of yours
is to free me of my chains,
and I give you even more
of my power, yes?
Yes.
What you call "a deal"
has always been my plan.
Why do you think
I chose to empower five of you
to begin with?
I am held by five chains,
chains that can only be cut
by five prismatic blades.
You have been defeated.
Humiliated.
So have I.
You crave more power
to crush your enemies?
So do I.
Find the blades, set me free,
and yes, I will grant you
the power you want.
How can we find them?
I'm certain this gem
will be most helpful
in your quest.
We don't want
any more trouble.
[transforming]
[grunting and straining]
[all screaming]
[grunting and snarling]
[♪♪♪]